<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Flatiron&nbsp;school&nbsp;hiphop | /grow|with|love/]]></title>
  <link href="http://rolandobrown.github.io/blog/categories/flatiron-school-hiphop/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://rolandobrown.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-08-11T05:31:13-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://rolandobrown.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Rolando Brown aka Grow]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Regex Ain't One of My Problems]]></title>
    <link href="http://rolandobrown.github.io/blog/2015/08/11/regex/"/>
    <updated>2015-08-11T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://rolandobrown.github.io/blog/2015/08/11/regex</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>tldr = &ldquo;This post is intended to familiarize you with two methods—gsub and regular expressions. It outlines how I used these two methods to programmatically transform four lines from the award winning, world renowned, chorus from &lsquo;Wu-Tang Clan Ain&rsquo;t Nuthing ta Fuck Wit,&rsquo; into a string that begins with &lsquo;Foo-Tang Clan ain&rsquo;t nuttin ta futz with.&rsquo; It also shares how I internalized knowledge of these methods, and their founders, by binding their definitions to my knowledge of Hiphop, Hip Hop Culture, D.J. Kool Herc, Afrikka Bambatta, KRS-One, Wu-Tang Clan and Jay-Z.</p>

<p><strong>NOTE:</strong></p>

<p>42 years ago, on August 11, 1973, D.J. Kool Herc didn’t know he was revolutionizing pop music—he was just trying to keep people dancing. That party, in the recreation room in an unassuming brick apartment building at 1520 Sedgwick Avenue, hard by the Major Deegan Expressway, a 16-year-old Jamaican immigrant changed pop music forever.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m two weeks into Flatiron School Web Immersive, and one of our instructors, Steven Nunez aka &ldquo;Hostile Developer&rdquo;, is introducing  Regular Expressions to a room full of soon to be Master Programmers. Last week, Steven ceremoniously named our cohort &ldquo;Foo-Tang Clan.&rdquo; Note, we were initially named &ldquo;web_0715.&rdquo;&ldquo; That&rsquo;s a significant improvement. An improvement that signals we&rsquo;ve tapped into the larger Hiphop consciousness.</p>

<p>During this afternoon lecture, Steven&rsquo;s blessing us with a lesson and I&rsquo;m naturally thinking about Hiphop, and something called &ldquo;Slang Expressions.&rdquo; Before I explain Regular Expressions, let me explain Slang Expressions so that you get a gist of the mental rinse and repeat I went through to while listening to his lecture.</p>

<p><div><script src='https://gist.github.com/3d647607800766c38501.js?file=slang_regular.rb'></script>
<noscript><pre><code>&quot;Slang Expressions&quot; != &quot;Regular Expressions&quot;</code></pre></noscript></div>
</p>

<p>Slang expressions are intentional constructions of language. Most slang expressions are not accidental variables, arrived at through random freestyle. Most are actually intentional, and intentionally contextual. You can think about slang expressions as annotations or descriptors intended to shovel a specific subgroup into a conversation, or to distinguish one group from another group. KRS-One, lovingly known as The Teacha, talks about slang expressions as street language: &ldquo;Our verbal communication, our codes throughout the nation.&rdquo; Note, it&rsquo;s been my experience that most slang expressions are created by Brolic Scholars, otherwise known as Honorary Sociolinguistic Prodigies using something similar to gsub methods.</p>

<p>So, Steven introduces &ldquo;Regular Expressions&rdquo;, and I&rsquo;m parallel processing. &ldquo;So far, we&rsquo;ve been talking Classes, Methods, and RSpec&hellip;&rdquo; Which reminds me of RESPECT. How do you respect code that can&rsquo;t pass a behavior-driven development test (BDD)?</p>

<p><strong>Quick Review:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><p><em>Classes</em> are the basic template from which object instances are created. A class is made up of a collection of variables representing internal state and methods providing behaviors that operate on that state.</p></li>
<li><p><em>A method</em> in Ruby is a set of expressions that returns a value. With methods, one can organize their code into subroutines that can be easily invoked from other areas of their program. Other languages sometimes refer to this as a function. A method may be defined as a part of a class or separately.</p></li>
<li><p><em>RSpec</em> is behavior driven development for Ruby. Dedicating time to writing appropriate and useful tests is a great way to catch errors early in the development process.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>We&rsquo;ve been talking Self, establishing environments, &ndash;failing-fast, Objects, jumping across Classes, breaking out of Loops, returning values, getting feedback, etc. We&rsquo;ve been talking syntax and semantics, literals and abstractions, and I can&rsquo;t help but think about the syntactic and semantic relationships between programming with Ruby, and utilizing the fifth element of Hip-Hop culture (Knowledge, or Knowledge, Culture, and &lsquo;Overstanding). This element, which can be seen as one of the cultures earliest and most powerful methods, was defined by Afrikka Bambatta, as a descendant of &ldquo;Peace, Love, Unity and Having Fun.&rdquo; The founding four elements of Hip Hop Culture were methods originally defined and compiled by Kool D.J. Herc. &ldquo;Herc&rsquo;s methods also pre-dated and partially introduced, sampling.&rdquo;</p>

<p><div><script src='https://gist.github.com/928ae13194e97b626f54.js?file=hiphop_elements.rb'></script>
<noscript><pre><code>elements = [&quot;Breaking&quot;, &quot;Mc&#39;ing&quot;, &quot;Graffiti Art&quot;, &quot;DJ&#39;ing&quot;, &quot;Knowledge&quot;]

def hip_hop_culture(elements)
  elements.map.with_index(1) { |elements, idx| puts &quot;#{idx}. #{elements}&quot;}
  # with_index(offset = 0) {|(*args), idx| ... }
end

puts hip_hop_culture(elements)

# &gt;&gt; 1. Breaking
# &gt;&gt; 2. Mc&#39;ing
# &gt;&gt; 3. Graffiti Art
# &gt;&gt; 4. DJ&#39;ing
# &gt;&gt; 5. Knowledge</code></pre></noscript></div>
</p>

<p>Now, this might seem like a distraction, but trust me, it&rsquo;s not. It&rsquo;s not a rabbit hole or a rant. It&rsquo;s a deeply nuanced critical connection between two bodies of knowledge. It&rsquo;s me bridging the gap between two forms of expression. Both intended to communicate, transform and normalize a set of behaviors. Right? I can&rsquo;t help but do this. So, rather than waste brain cycles fighting my nature, I decided to lean into it.</p>

<p>This &ldquo;can&rsquo;t help but lean in,&rdquo; better described as &ldquo;can&rsquo;t stop won&rsquo;t stop&rdquo; is a manifestation of two personal habits: reconciling languages and seeking the internalization of knowledge. It&rsquo;s also the result of a larger cultural phenomena I imagine both Programmers and Hiphoppas share: the desire to do the Knowledge.</p>

<p>Why does one &ldquo;do the Knowledge&rdquo; before we talk about the gsub and the Regular Expression?
Well, because in Hip Hop Culture, we always do the Knowledge first.</p>

<p>In Hip Hop, you do the knowledge to gain access to the essence. That essence is a superpower: the ability to fully express yourself.
In Programming, you do the knowledge to gain access to the essence. That essence is a superpower: the ability to fully express yourself.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;d like to learn to express myself over time at a higher and higher level of abstraction.</p>

<p><div><script src='https://gist.github.com/fc4fbbc44873d145b926.js?file=dotheknowledge.rb'></script>
<noscript><pre><code>knowledge = []
%w{tools experiences teachers rabbitholes}.each do |lesson|
  knowledge &lt;&lt; lesson and puts &quot;Added to knowledge&quot; unless lesson.include?(&quot;rabbithole&quot;)
end
puts knowledge.inspect

# &gt;&gt; [&quot;tools&quot;, &quot;experiences&quot;, &quot;teachers&quot;]</code></pre></noscript></div>
</p>

<p>So here&rsquo;s a few lessons learned on my road to being fully expressed as a Master Programmer, and an invitation to learn more about Hiphop.
Now, let&rsquo;s do the knowledge.</p>

<h1>Here&rsquo;s how I used the gsub &amp; Regular Expression methods to create a remixed theme song for the Foo-Tang Clan.</h1>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/88jr9QUxbcs" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<h2>Side A: gsub &amp; Regular Expressions</h2>

<p>The sub and gsub methods (.sub &amp; .gsub) are used to replace Strings, or String objects if we want to be literal.
In computer programming, a string is traditionally a sequence of characters, either as a literal constant or as some kind of variable.
A String object holds and manipulates an arbitrary sequence of bytes, typically representing characters.</p>

<p>Not characters like this below.</p>

<p>{insert image of Steven Octo image over the 9 members of the wu-tang clan}</p>

<p>More like these types of characters:</p>

<blockquote><p>And if you want beef, then bring the ruckus
Wu Tang Clan ain&rsquo;t nuttin ta fuck with
Straight from the motherfucking slums that&rsquo;s busted
Wu-Tang Clan ain&rsquo;t nuttin ta fuck with*</p></blockquote>

<p><strong>gsub(pattern, replacement) → new_str</strong></p>

<p><a href="http://ruby-doc.org/core-2.1.4/String.html#method-i-gsub">This shows the Ruby Method for gsub.</a></p>

<p>The method above returns a new_str (a new copy of str) with all occurrences of pattern replaced with either replacement or the value of the block. The pattern will typically be a Regular Expressions (regexp).</p>

<p>Regular expressions originated in 1956 when mathematician Stephen Cole Kleene described regular languages using his mathematical notation called regular sets. Regular expressions entered popular use as early as 1968 in several iterations by the following people: Ken Thompson, Douglas T. Ross, Henry Spencer, Jeffrey Fried, and Philip Hazel. Regular expression support is part of the standard library of many programming languages, including Java and Python, and Ruby.</p>

<p>Regular expressions are used to search for text patterns. Programmers use regular expressions to validate emails and URLs, capture information and use simple patterns to save themselves development time. Below are a few resources intended to avoid regular expressions being one of your problems.</p>

<p><strong>Study Your Lessons:</strong></p>

<p>I recommend the following process:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.codeschool.com/courses/breaking-the-ice-with-regular-expressions">Code School Course &ldquo;Breaking the Ice W/ Regular Expressions&rdquo;</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.regexr.com">Learn, build, &amp; test Regular Expressions (RegEx / RegExp)"</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fOH62XXGdLs">Watch this RegExr Tutorial"</a></li>
<li>Use some of your favorite text to find patterns using RegExr (Poems, Songs, Speeches, Essays, etc.)</li>
<li><a href="http://rubular.com">Then see this Regular Expressions tool for Ruby</a></li>
</ul>


<p>Below are additional articles that provide more context and opportunities to practice.</p>

<h2>Side B: Knowing when to use Regular Expressions</h2>

<p>Now, knowing how a Regular Expression is written is only half-time. To gain any real win from them you have to know how to use them too. Regular expressions are used for complex replacements. Replacing multiple lyrics with different patterns in a song is a complex replacement. Hence, I used a gsub method with a regex pattern.</p>

<p>There&rsquo;s this popular wisdom about Regular expressions, a quote that&rsquo;s pretty much internet famous among Programmers. I read it. It goes a little something like this:</p>

<p><em>Some people, when confronted with a problem, think
“I know, I&rsquo;ll use regular expressions.” Now they have two problems.
-Jamie Zawinski</em></p>

<p>Here are a few ideas that came to mind reading this quote.</p>

<p>In other words, this is how grow.rb thinks about the relationship between Jamie Zawinski &amp; Jay-Z</p>

<iframe src="//slides.com/rolandobrown/deck/embed" width="700" height="500" scrolling="no" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p><strong>Ok, now that this is done. Here&rsquo;s how I used the following regular expressions:</strong></p>

<p><div><script src='https://gist.github.com/06acc7704e7716a4e561.js?file=gsub_regexp.rb'></script>
<noscript><pre><code>  def alias
    # kinda colorful transformations using gsub &amp; regexp
    @chorus.gsub(/(wu(-|\s)tang\sclan)/i,
    @name).gsub(/motherfucking slums/i,
    @switchup).gsub(/fuck/i,
    @aka).gsub(/busted/i, &quot;trusted&quot;)
  end</code></pre></noscript></div>
</p>

<p>Once I figured out this Method of transforming, I went ahead and build the Class Cohort, and following methods: <em>initialize</em>, <em>chorus</em>, <em>expletives</em> and <em>environment</em>. I designed these methods to take arguments. I imagine that a future Cohort might want to transform their favorite song into a Flatiron theme song.</p>

<p><div><script src='https://gist.github.com/b97f23367db94b6a8555.js?file=footang.rb'></script>
<noscript><pre><code>class Cohort
  def initialize(name)
    @name = name
  end

  def chorus(chorus)
    @chorus = chorus  # =&gt; &quot;And if you want beef, then bring the ruckus\nWu Tang Clan ain&#39;t nuttin ta fuck with\nStraight from the motherfucking slums that&#39;s busted\nWu-Tang Clan ain&#39;t nuttin ta fuck with&quot;
  end

  def expletives(aka)
    # colorful array of expletives
    @aka = aka
  end

  def environment (switchup)
    @switchup = switchup
  end

  def alias
    # kinda colorful transformations using gsub &amp; regex
    @chorus.gsub(/(wu(-|\s)tang\sclan)/i, @name).gsub(/motherfucking slums/i, @switchup).gsub(/fuck/i, @aka).gsub(/busted/i, &quot;trusted&quot;)
  end

end

song = Cohort.new(&quot;Foo-Tang Clan&quot;)
song.chorus (&quot;And if you want beef, then bring the ruckus\nWu Tang Clan ain&#39;t nuttin ta fuck with\nStraight from the motherfucking slums that&#39;s busted\nWu-Tang Clan ain&#39;t nuttin ta fuck with&quot;)
song.expletives (&quot;futz&quot;)                                                                                                                                                                          song.environment (&quot;Flatiron School&quot;)                                                                                                                                                             puts song.alias

# &gt;&gt; And if you want beef, then bring the ruckus
# &gt;&gt; Foo-Tang Clan ain&#39;t nuttin ta futz with
# &gt;&gt; Straight from the Flatiron School that&#39;s trusted
# &gt;&gt; Foo-Tang Clan ain&#39;t nuttin ta futz with

## Notes
# I grew up singing the chorus in it&#39;s trueschool form, and prefer that. Still, this is an example of using gsub &amp; regular expressions.
# Original chorus here: genius.com/Wu-tang-clan-wu-tang-clan-aint-nuthing-ta-fuck-wit-lyrics
</code></pre></noscript></div>
</p>

<p>Enough respect to   Nikila Saravanan &amp; George Tootheman.
Nikila helped me craft the code above, and George accelerated my Octopress deployment.
Part of doing the knowledge, especially in Hip-Hop culture, is giving credit where credit is due.
I&rsquo;ve found the same to be true in Programming.</p>

<p>Thank you Nikila &amp; George!</p>

<h3>CONTAINS SAMPLES &amp; INSPIRATION FROM:</h3>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=88jr9QUxbcs">&ldquo;Wu-Tang Clan Ain&rsquo;t Nuthing ta Fuck Wit” Video</a></li>
<li><p><a href="http://genius.com/Wu-tang-clan-wu-tang-clan-aint-nuthing-ta-fuck-wit-lyrics">&ldquo;Wu-Tang Clan Ain&rsquo;t Nuthing ta Fuck Wit” Lyrics</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://web0715.students.flatironschool.com">Foo-Tang Clan</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://regex.info/blog/2006-09-15/247">Jamie Zawinski, “Now you have two problems” quote</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://www.zytrax.com/tech/web/regex.htm">General Regex</a></p></li>
<li><a href="http://ruby-doc.com/docs/ProgrammingRuby/#UJ">Ruby Regex</a></li>
<li><a href="http://blog.codinghorror.com/regular-expressions-now-you-have-two-problems">Jeff Atwood, Two Problems</a></li>
<li><a href="http://blog.codinghorror.com/if-you-like-regular-expressions-so-much-why-dont-you-marry-them">Marry Regular Expressions</a></li>
<li><p><a href="http://slides.com/stefangretcan/regex#/">Regex Slide</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://code.tutsplus.com/tutorials/8-regular-expressions-you-should-know--net-6149">8 regexes to know</a></p></li>
<li><a href="http://www.rubyinside.com/21-ruby-tricks-902.html">21 Ruby Tricks</a></li>
<li><a href="http://blog.smartbear.com/development/the-developers-regex-survival-guide-15-rules-for-making-sense-of-regular-expressions">15 Rules of regex</a></li>
<li><p><a href="http://rspec.info">RSpec</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CS7jN-bZ8mM">KRS-One on Afrikka Bambatta</a></p></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DGQ0tBfoRVw">KRS-One on 9 Elements</a></li>
<li><p><a href="https://youtu.be/REpSdgORU5A?t=1h5m19s">KRS-One on Hiphop conciousness</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://www.hiphop-network.com/articles/djarticles/kooldjherc.asp">Kool D.J. Herc</a></p></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zulunation.com/afrika-bambaataa">Afrikka Bambatta</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.jwz.org/blog">Jamie Zawinski</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.wutang-corp.com">Wu-Tang Clan</a></li>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jay_Z">Jay-z</a></li>
<li><a href="http://hostiledeveloper.com">Steven Nunez</a></li>
<li><a href="http://web0715.students.flatironschool.com/students/niki_saravanan.html">Niki Saravanan</a></li>
<li><p><a href="http://web0715.students.flatironschool.com/students/george_toothman.html">George Tootheman</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://nymag.com/anniversary/40th/50665">The Holy House of Hip-hop, August 11, 1973</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://cantstopwontstop.com/">Can&rsquo;t Stop Won&rsquo;t Stop</a></p></li>
</ul>


<p><div><script src='https://gist.github.com/dc999c5ed85a530896c8.js?file=footang_disclaimer.rb'></script>
<noscript><pre><code>puts &quot;I grew up understanding that Wu-Tang Is Forever, never to be imitated or duplicated. This is simply an example of using gsub &amp; regular expressions.&quot;</code></pre></noscript></div>
</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
